My wife and I have an agreement on when it comes to washing dishes that I load the dishwasher and she
unloads the dishwasher.
Now I have a very particular way of how I load the dishes.
I mean I have a system down of when I rinse them and get them into the dishwasher and I'm sure she has
a way of what she unloads first and when she puts away the silverware and so on.
The point being that I've developed a system a way of doing the work to do that little chore an organizational
system is that same concept but on a much larger scale and organizational system gives structure and
governance.
It's how you get work done.
So in your organization in your company you likely have a system that you follow in order to procure
in order to request time off in order to get a resource on your project.
So an organizational system is from a very large point of view.
How does your organization work what's evolved over time or have been designed over time so provide
structure.
It also gives some governance some rules permissions are tied here so how do I do something to my allowed
to do something.
How much authority do I have as the PM.
So what permissions do I need work authorization.
What's the structure that when Reisch completes his assignment.
It allows David to start his.
So what's the handoff there between those two team members.
Do we have to have a status meeting and that Raj communicates to me the PM and then I communicate to
David.
So what's the process there.
Or are these two allowed to talk to each other or is it electronic.
So what's the permissions and the work authorization.
How do those fit together in your structure.
What about employee discipline if we have a team member that's consistently late or consistently making
errors or they're not doing their assignments.
So what's the process they are you allowed to discipline that team member or do you have to go to their
functional manager.
If you go to H.R. or the sponsor so what's that like in your organization.
So all of this is defined by the organization management.
And obviously that affects what you do in the project how that affects you as the than we have system
dynamics system dynamics is just a way of talk about the relationship between the different components
between the different departments in your organization.
So sometimes system they need a mix can be you know not friendly so or it's a lot of bureaucracy feels
very stilted and kind of formal and stuffy.
Other times it can be great.
We're following we're all on the same team here.
So you give me this and I'll do this and we'll work together and get it done.
So system dynamics us how about the relationship typically we think about between departments between
projects but also between management and employees how employees look at you as a manager or part of
management.
So bureaucracy you know the red tape the forms the processes you're only allowed to do certain things
or we don't allow that to happen.
You know bureaucracy is always kind of a pain in the neck but it's there for a reason sometimes because
it's part of the system framework politics.
We're going to come into play over and over you know politics are those power struggles and so on then
tied to that we have policies their policies have been established for a reason.
And you and the project team have to follow and adhere to those policies.
All right good job I'll see you in the next lecture.